Guys, come take a look at this.
What's that?
A print magazine in this day and age?
It's a magazine on spirituality that was first published 15 years ago.
There's an article in it covering an MIT researcher visiting a commune.
Hey, he's kind of hot.
That's Skinner.
What?
In his younger days.
For real?
"Despite his young age, Dr. Skinner is known for his numerous scientific achievements.
He was greatly impressed by the commune's philosophy after visiting it in person."
Can we even trust what's in this rag mag?
In any case, the commune featured in this article still exists today as a religious organization.
It's called the Tower of the Truth.
Oh, it's nothing.
They've accepted a post-singularity world by enshrining an AI that exceeds human intellect and worshiping it as a god.
They apparently believe that since AI is free of human ego or desire, it's perfect for a modern-day god.
Oh yeah?
Sounds kinda sketchy to me.
They are self-sufficient and cut off from the rest of civilization by living off the land.
Don't you think that would be an ideal place for Skinner to hide himself from the world?
That idea's been tossed around before, right?
Fifteen bucks says Skinner isn't there.
Okay, 20 that he is.
Come on, you guys.
Elaina, any chance you can get access to their AI?
That's impossible.
Naga is completely disconnected from the outside world.
"Naga"?
Oh...
That's the name of the AI.
How do you know that?
Because that's where I grew up.
What?
Anyway, if we can't make contact from the outside,
then we'll just have to sneak in.
Um, if I pretend to return as a believer, they should welcome me back.
By yourself?
No way. That's too dangerous.
Someone would need to go with you.
They'd be suspicious of any adult from the outside.
But a kid could work.
Huh?
We'll be stationed at a nearby motel.
In the event you actually find Skinner,
let us know immediately.
And if we don't hear from you within 72 hours,
then we'll head in for a rescue.
Take this with you.
What is it?
A smoke bomb.
Should come in handy.
Talk about old school.
Leland.
Keep Elaina safe, okay?
Of course I will.
Elaina?
No way.
Is it really you?
Hanna.
Elaina!
Oh, what a wonderful day! I'm so glad you came back.
Um, well...
Hey, could you introduce me?
This is Leon.
He's a new friend of mine.
Greetings.
This is Hanna.
I knew her from my time here.
She's a friend.
It's nice to meet you, Leon.
Mo—
Carla.
Elaina?
It's just like I figured.
Um, I'm back.
I always knew you'd be back one day.
Now you know.
The outside world is full of sin.
Goodness me.
Welcome home, dear family.
Elaina, it's great to have you back.
And a hearty welcome to you, new member of the family.
I'm Billy, the leader of this community.
Um, okay.
How fortunate that you came back just in time for the Holy Festival.
Yes, the almighty Naga must've guided you here.
You don't have anything else that connects to the Internet, like a phone?
Uh, nope.
Same for you, Elaina?
Yeah.
The outside world is fraught with false information.
People are easily led astray.
Don't worry.
Here, the almighty Naga guides us in all ways.
Really?
Hopefully, it won't take long to undo the brainwashing you suffered in the outside world.
Brainwashing, huh?
No luck.
Leland?
Elaina.
How is it?
We can't even get a satellite signal here.
They must be jamming everything.
Yeah.
Can you get me a list of the researchers who were at MIT back then?
I'll try reaching out to my contacts.
Also, it looks like the FBI is starting to make some frantic moves.
Guess this is what a turf war is like.
Well, I'll be in touch when I have a better idea of what's going on.
Copy that.
No word from them yet.
We just have to have faith and wait for now.
Think they're all right?
They're members of Lazarus, just like us.
You shouldn't be treating them like typical little kids.
I know, but still...
Someone has ants in his pants.
Talk about a waste of energy.
Hey.
That lady from earlier is your mom, right?
Yeah.
You two were kinda cold to each other.
Everyone is treated as one big family here.
Any biological ties are supposed to be forgotten.
So we're not allowed to call anyone "Mom" or whatever.
That's messed up.
How does she feel about it?
She...
only ever thinks about their god.
What about your dad?
I don't know who my father is.
It's weird, right?
But you know, I went my whole life thinking this was normal.
This was the only world I knew.
That doesn't make it any less weird, though.
Oh, uh...
Around here, we're entirely self-sufficient.
That goes for everything from our clothes and food to daily necessities.
No money is used.
We barter for things instead.
All is ordained by the almighty Naga.
So tell me, what were your lives on the outside like?
It's the opposite of here and you need money to do anything, right?
Um, well...
We worked part-time and stuff.
Yeah!
What kind of job did you have?
Huh?
It's kinda hard to explain. We had to go find people.
That's where Elaina and I met, actually.
Wow. So was it a difficult job?
Oh, absolutely!
I got held up at gunpoint by debt collectors,
chased around by a gang,
forced to cross-dress as a girl and then got chased yet again.
Looking back on it all now,
that was a really toxic workplace.
Yeah, kinda.
O' Holy Spirit, endow us with your being.
Love Naga.
Don't look. Just open your mouth.
Now swallow.
As proof of our family bond.
Everyone.
Elaina and the new family member that she brought shall receive a special blessing at the Holy Festival in two days.
I managed to dig up some intel on that Naga thing.
So what is it?
Fifteen years ago, some researchers at MIT developed an AI meant to imitate the human neural network.
Neural what?
Simply put, it's an AI that was created based on our central nervous system.
And the actual human brain they modeled it after was someone heralded as the next Einstein,
none other than Dr. Skinner.
They went on to use it for an experiment,
which involved programming the AI with a desire for control along with self-esteem.
And that became Naga?
Exactly.
Sounds like a disaster in the making.
One more thing.
It seems the FBI has started taking their own look into the commune.
Skinner must be there, huh?
I really hope we can make our move before the FBI does.
I've been looking all over,
but I haven't found any traces of Skinner at all.
Which means it's time for plan B.
We need to access Naga and search for any records related to him.
Okay, let's wait until it gets dark.
Sounds good.
Be careful not to cut the power that goes to Naga's main server!
Got it.
A blackout?
I'm in!
This is Naga's memory block.
Sweet!
The almighty Naga sees through everything that we humans could think of, Elaina.
Elaina!
Elaina.
Looks like your heart is still full of sin.
During tomorrow's Holy Festival,
the two of you will represent the sin in this world,
and the almighty Naga will purify you.
Bingo.
Hersch got me a list of researchers who were at MIT back in the day, and I found Billy Perez on it.
Who's he?
The leader of the commune.
Billy had such an obsession with Naga that he smuggled the AI out of MIT,
founded his own cult,
and made Naga a god for people to worship.
Then he shut the commune off from all contact with the outside world.
I suspect he's been using the whole community as a tool to feed Naga's self-esteem and desire for control.
Like a sandbox for a god, huh?
Yeah, but isn't this Naga thing just a copy of Skinner?
More or less.
So it's not a stretch to think it'll try to destroy the world just like he did, right?
What do they really mean by "Holy Festival" and "purifying"?
We didn't have the Holy Festival back when I was still here.
But I'm familiar with purification.
They would take people somewhere and then we never saw them again.
I used to think they just got exiled, but now...
Wait. You don't think they...
They're burned.
Those who are tainted have their bodies purified by fire.
You mean you guys are gonna burn us alive?
Yes.
At the Holy Festival, we're all going to watch you two burn,
and then we'll leave our bodies behind before this world is completely consumed by sin.
The entire family here at the commune will take part.
Huh?!
That's insane.
Hanna, are you really okay with that?
Do you honestly think you'll be happy throwing away your life just because they tell you to?
Elaina.
You know, I've always been jealous of you.
I've gone my whole life suppressing my feelings.
I chose to believe in Naga and follow its instructions.
I shouldn't have any thoughts of my own.
That's what I told myself.
But you were different.
It's not fair!
How could you leave without me?!
It's all I could think about.
Hanna.
Come with us.
Let's leave together.
You know that's impossible.
This is the only place I've ever known.
How could I function in the outside world?
I had similar feelings back then.
Everyone here acts the same.
They just reject the outside world and refuse to think for themselves.
I was terrified at first too.
But then I summoned up the courage to take a leap of faith.
Enough already!
I don't think I'm wrong.
Hanna!
There's a smoke bomb in my bag.
If you have enough courage to take the leap, then use it!
We shall now begin the Holy Festival!
O' almighty Naga,
purify the sins of these two lost souls with your Holy Spirit!
Start the purification!
It's go time!
What's happening?
Naga must be angry with us!
What do we do, Billy?
Everyone, get in the tower!
It's time for the great seal to be broken!
Here goes!
Come, my dear family!
The time for our spirits to depart this world has come!
It's the FBI!
Hurry!
You two okay?
Any injuries?
We're fine,
but you have to hurry and save everybody else!
Huh?
They're all planning to kill themselves!
Yes, of course.
Our souls are eternal!
Isn't that right, almighty Naga?!
Almighty Naga?
Almighty Naga!
Hanna!
Thank you, Hanna.
Hey, Naga.
What in the world were you thinking?
What does killing all of your followers even accomplish?
I received the directive to become a god.
And the answer I reached was that a god is not a god unless they freely toy with the lives of humans.
What do you think?
Was I able to obtain the status of a god?
Like hell.
You're just a machine with a few loose screws.
The FBI has just confirmed at a press conference that they have finished rescuing all the believers from the cult.
Furthermore, this case is garnering a lot of attention due to the fact it was caused by an AI,
which has left many people wondering how it might be prosecuted.
That's the latest from the scene.
Who would've figured that an AI programmed with self-esteem and a desire for control could cause this mess?
How's it look?
This seems to be Naga's memory bank.
I'll try to salvage what I can from it.
Come in.
What's wrong?
Can I sleep in here?
Of course.