How will the end of the world come upon us?
It's something that I've always wondered about since I was a kid.
But the end arrived without warning,
in a way that nobody could've imagined.
The whole thing started roughly four years ago.
That was when Dr. Skinner, a man touted as having the most brilliant mind since Einstein,
began to sell a miracle painkiller that he'd developed known as "Hapna."
Since it was cheap and had no side effects whatsoever,
it dominated the market instantly,
and the world became a Hapna-filled wonderland.
It liberated people from all kinds of suffering and was even celebrated as "the drug that saved the world."
But then, three years ago,
Dr. Skinner abruptly vanished without a trace.
Not a soul knew where he'd gone.
And, as it turned out, Hapna was a huge trap that he set upon the world.
Hey, put on some music for me.
What kind of music would you like?
Let's see.
Something that's got the vibe of a guy who sold his soul to the devil.
Or along those lines.
That's the kind of song I want.
Axel Gilberto.
You've got a visitor.
For me?
You've only got ten minutes.
We clear?
Okay.
That's plenty.
Um...
Sorry, but have we met before?
We're complete strangers.
This is the first time we've met.
Every stranger who's taken the time to visit me always turns out to be either a lawyer or a hitman.
Well, I suppose you might say that I'm both.
Huh?
My name is Hersch.
I've come here today to ask for a favor.
And depending on how you answer,
I could free you from your current situation.
Free me, huh?
Got any idea how long I'm serving?
Exactly 888 years.
In other words, a life sentence.
I know everything there is to know about you.
Your birthplace, work history,
medical history, shoe size, you name it.
What an honor.
So, what's this favor of yours?
I take it you're familiar with Hapna.
Of course.
It's all the rage here in prison.
What about Skinner's announcement?
News to me.
Just recently, this clip was posted to every video platform around the world.
After vanishing off the face of the Earth for the past three years, Dr. Skinner made his return.
If you find yourself unable to feel any pain at all,
then that is no different from being dead.
While it is most unfortunate, humanity is basically dead now due to its dependence upon Hapna.
Furthermore, humanity has become fixated on making short-term gains in an endless fight amongst each other,
which has irreparably destroyed the environment and taken the lives of countless people in the process.
And so, as a scientist, I'm forced to come to the conclusion that this is the true nature of human beings.
No way...
Can such atrocities be allowed?
Shouldn't we, the human race,
be held accountable and face harsh punishment?
The truth is, I did not develop Hapna to act as a mere painkiller.
It was engineered to remain within the body, and then three years after it was first taken,
it mutates into a toxin that is 100% lethal.
Here we go.
It is impossible for the toxin to be neutralized or expelled from the body.
I have no intention of playing God.
Nor do I intend to unilaterally decide what the fate of humanity will be.
All I am doing is serving as the Seventh Trumpeter.
You gotta be kidding.
I estimate the first people will die in approximately 30 days.
But you should know that I currently hold a cure.
You have 30 days.
If someone can find me within that time,
then humanity will survive.
Excuse me, sir!
Huh?
Sorry to interrupt, but I'm going home.
And I don't think I'll ever be back.
B-But why?
I mean...
What point is there in coming to school anymore?
Whether humanity is something worth saving or not...
is a decision that I leave for all of you to decide.
In the past, Skinner constantly sought peace and equality for all.
He was a real saint of a man.
And now that he's back, he's turned into the devil?
I want you to find him.
That's the favor I came here to ask you.
Time's up.
You've looked into everything about me, yeah?
Yes.
Then you must already know that I have a pretty bad habit of breaking out of prison.
Hurry it up.
Why all the rush?
Watch yourself, punk!
Whoa there!
No false moves.
Wouldja mind taking these off me?
Freeze!
He fled to the third floor! After him!
Hey, buddy! Let me out too!
You stupid little shit!
Yes?
He got away. Bring the car around immediately.
He flew away in the blink of an eye.
Just like a bird that was let out of its cage.
Roger that.
Leland!
Oh, hey, Chris.
Sup?
Looks like someone's in a good mood.
Huh? I do?
Totally.
Does humanity being doomed really make you that happy?
Nah, that's not why.
Then what?
It's just, ya know, I realized there's no point in forcing myself to show up for school anymore.
Know what I mean?
You're such a kid!
Ouch!
What'd I say?
Look, a kitty!
Aww, it's so cute!
I take that back.
Eleina, keep tabs on all police communications and GPS.
Roger.
Unbelievable.
What a pain in the ass.
He could've been shot dead by the police at this point.
I doubt it.
He's not that kind of man.
It looks like the police haven't found him yet, either.
Understood.
Keep monitoring them.
There's breaking news.
After Dr. Skinner's shocking statement earlier today,
several cities have descended into chaos.
Full-on riots have broken out in some places,
while elsewhere, people have begun lighting pharmaceutical companies on fire.
My fellow citizens,
I am urging you all to please remain calm.
We've already assembled a team of experts who are doing everything they can to swiftly develop a cure for Hapna.
I can only assume Dr. Skinner has lost his mind.
I have no idea why he would do something like this.
Is it really true that all the people who've taken Hapna can't be saved?
I mean, the government seems to think it's possible for their people to develop a cure.
Thirty days is simply not enough time.
Even if a cure could be developed,
it's likely that nobody will be left alive when it's ready.
In the wake of Skinner's video, pharmaceutical companies have put an end to all Hapna sales across the board.
Furthermore, their representatives have announced a complete recall of all products currently on the market.
The end is nigh as Satan calls forth Armageddon!
We must come to terms with our fate as there is no stopping it!
A historical crash was reported at the NYSE today with the Dow Jones plunging to its lowest numbers ever.
This crash eclipses even the infamous Black Monday.
Hey there, fella!
What's with the getup?
Uh...
Is that prisoner look a fashion trend these days or something?
Oh, for sure! It's hip!
Either that, or maybe you really did escape from a prison.
Yeah, right!
Well, I guess that would be ridiculous.
Totally. I mean, what kinda fugitive would be that stupid?
Anyway, riots have been breaking out all over.
It's best you don't go wandering around.
I'll be careful.
Head on home!
Attention all units.
It's been reported that an escapee from Northport Correctional Facility has fled into the city.
The suspect's name is Axel Gilberto, age 23.
Forwarding a picture to you now.
That son of a—
Well, shoot.
It seems things are moving even faster than we anticipated.
Not to mention, they'll undoubtedly move to destroy all the evidence if they get wind that we're on their tracks.
Secrecy and speed will be of the utmost importance as we proceed with this investigation.
I understand.
How is the analysis of Hapna going?
We're working on it,
but it's proving to be a huge challenge.
The thing is basically a true work of art created by a genius.
Developing a cure in such a short period of time is going to be next to impossible.
In other words, we're also at the point where the only viable option is finding Dr. Skinner.
Precisely.
That last member of yours... What happened with him?
He got away.
But I promise that we'll get him.
All right.
You know, those people might very well be our last hope.
Fugitive Axel Gilberto, stop resisting and surrender immediately.
Who, me?
Bring it on!
Hey!
There he goes! That way!
The target has shown up.
He's at Union Station.
Roger that. On my way.
Weird.
It looks like he's running somewhere way off the roads.
Okay. Time to greet our guest.
Axel Gilberto, stop immediately!
So the dude just waltzed right into Union Station?
Yeah. It's about time he showed up.
Eleina, can you run the data and predict where he's headed to?
Sure thing.
I'll send it as soon as I can.
The computer has predicted his course.
Sending it to you now.
Roger that.
Chris, do you copy?
You're about to get some coordinates.
Head there first.
Then do what you can to force him north-northwest.
And my permission to open fire?
Already taken care of.
Isn't that lovely?
Just try not to hit anyone!
And don't damage any property!
Axel Gilberto, stop immediately!
Back me up.
You got it!
Freeze!
Show's over.
Put your hands in the air.
Oh, I get it.
You cut off my route to get me to come to this building.
And it worked perfectly.
Hold up.
I don't get to see the face of the guy who's gonna kill me?
Can I at least get a name?
Douglas Hadine.
Do me a solid and put this on my gravestone:
"Here lies a helpless man shot and killed from behind by the cowardly Doug Whatshisface."
I'm not falling for that.
You're being provocative on purpose so that you can lure me into a close-quarters fight.
You got me.
In any case, this is the end of the line for you.
Seeing as how humans weren't built to fly.
Normally speaking.
Only losers care about being normal.
You wanna test that theory?
Hey, Mr. Daredevil! Look over here!
You're so badass!
Oh my god!
That was, like, the most awesome street performance I've ever seen!
Uh, well...
I was actually just running from a dude.
So, hey...
Mind if we took a selfie together?
Huh?
Well, actually—
Sweet!
Okay!
Ready? Three, two, one...
Smile!
The hell is this thing?
Hey, he's finally awake!
Wanna know what's crazy?
You were out cold for pretty much an entire day!
Since you wouldn't wake up at all, we kinda thought you were dead.
I recognize you guys. You were in my dream.
That wasn't a dream.
We finally meet again.
I seriously have no idea what the hell is going on here.
Who even are you people?
We are Lazarus.
Welcome aboard, Axel Gilberto.
What?